

ALVISE SEMBENICO

RESEARCH INTERN ● AMSTERDAM, 1083HP, NETHERLANDS • 0649871233

• DETAILS •

Vivaldistraat 5b47 Amsterdam, 1083hp Netherlands 0649871233

alvise.sembenico@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth 04-10-1996 Trento

> Nationality Italian

Driving license B

• LANGUAGES •

Italian English German

• HOBBIES •

Fitness, Neuroscience, Business and communication science.

• LINKS •

<u>LinkedIn</u>

alvisesembenico.com

PROFILE

I consider myself a comprehensively interested person who loves new challenges and complex tasks. I have been always curious about different accepts of modern society, like social behaviour, cognitive bias and most of all about computer science. Thanks to my various developing experience I am accustomed to teamwork, problem-solving and decision-making working attitude. During my master, I have realized that I highly enjoy doing research and being in the academics world. I'm fascinated by the potential of artificial intelligence and I'll be happy to contribute to the AI research.

★ DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, Java, C++, C, Javascript, Typescript.

Machine learning frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Conda packages.

Devops experience: Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

CEO and Co-founder at Intrical AL, Amsterdam

September 2020 — Present

As CEO of the company, I lead the AI development team in order to create a unified platform for automatic companies' profiles to serve experts in Mergers and Acquisitions using state the art Natural Language Processing techniques.

Machine Learning and Deep Learning Teacher Assistant at University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

February 2020 — December 2020

Researcher intern at Quva Lab, Amsterdam

September 2019 — August 2020

My tasks consist of improving some limitation and overcome the drawbacks of the state of the art Deep Learning object trackers. The main problem I have been working on is defining a mathematical framework that limits the model decay during online learning leading to a higher score, especially in long term video tracking.

Full stack Developer at Maykinmedia, Amsterdam

November 2018 — July 2019

My role as developer consists of building the full infrastructure to maintain a web service, including back-end and front-end development, continuous integration, integration testing, deployment.

Python and django Web Programmer at Freelancer, Trento

September 2016 — September 2018

I developed different web application, and Rest API, thanks to Rest Framework. As DB I used Postgres due to its better integration in Django framework.

Web developer, Trento

September 2016 — September 2018

I developed several Web-based application using Java EE and NodeJS. I built Rest API services and front-end website with HTML and JavaScript. In every project there is a strong component related to data management, therefore I used MySql and Postgres ad DBMS

Junior Web Developer at Opera Universitaria, Trento

February 2017 — October 2017

- Web application of a canteen system development, using Java EE and Mysql
- I built a digital signage aimed to displaying daily advertise and menu in University Canteen
- I cured alse the Front-end even if the design is not my first aim.

Dot Net Web Developer at Gam Lab S.R.L., Rovereto

June 2017 — June 2018

- I maintaned server and client side of payroll web application (.NET, ASP, HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript)
- multi-platform smartphone application development (Cordova)

Junior Web Developer at Polo Tecnologico per l'energia, Trento

August 2014 — September 2014

- · developed a website aiming to environment safeguard
- collaborate and communicate with stakeholders implementing best UI and utilities

EDUCATION

Artificial Intelligence, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam

September 2018 — August 2020

Deeply research-driven programme, with a focus on the mathematical foundations. I worked on my thesis together with Quva Lab on "Multifaceted Memory Augmentation in Discriminative Object Tracking".

Computer Science, Università degli studi di Trento, Trento

September 2015 — July 2018

The main courses are: Programming 1, Object-Oriented programming, Functional Programming, Software Engineering 1-2, Algorithms and data structures, Database, Web-programming, Android Programming, Formal Languages and Compilers, Networks, Computer Architecture, Logic, Linear Algebra, Physic, Probability and Statistic. Lot of importance has been posed to the quality of the code, the team work, the importance of the standard, and the deep knowledge of all the layers that compose any application or process.

REFERENCES

0

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Al Startup Lab at ACE Venture, Amsterdam

March 2020 — Present

The AI Startup lab challenges students, recent graduates and early-stage startups to lay the foundation for an AI startup in as little as 10 weeks.

Participants are supported and guided by academic experts in the field of AI, as well as top-notch entrepreneurs. The AI Startup Lab is the ultimate opportunity to kickstart your entrepreneurial career in AI.

Start Up Lab at UniTn, Trento

January 2018 — May 2018

The Start-Up Lab is a hands-on interdepartmental Lab on Innovation and Entrepreneurship an counts as one of the main pillars of the CLab of the University of

Trento. SUL is an innovative learning experience focused on customer centric creativity, idea generation, business idea optimization and pitching. It is finalized to develop innovative products/services which can, eventually, turn into a start-up. Students are constantly mentored by professionals and entrepreneurs.

Innovation Olympics at UniTn, Trento

September 2017 — December 2018

Corporations from different industries define an exciting and difficult challenge they are currently facing in the market - this is the "Innovation Challenge". 4-5 groups of 4-5 students from different disciplines, countries and cultures focus on the challenge for 8-10 weeks. They cooperate with the team mates and compete with other teams to propose well grounded, creative and unique solutions. Experienced mentors and coaches provide expert guidance along with tools, training, and coaching to build more lasting innovation capability and leadership skills.

Data Driven Hackaton, Amsterdam

November 2018 — November 2018

I participated and won the Hackaton organized in the University venues. The task was to extract crucial information from raw data and predict possible triggering situation for people with mental diseases.